ADAM XIAO

(484)-319-9224 ● adam.x.xiao@gmail.com ● github.com/adam-xiao

SUMMARY

Experienced in Full Stack Web Development with a background in biological sciences / engineering. Possess strong skills in team facilitation, customer relations, optimization and analogous problem solving that help companies approach projects in an holistic, organized fashion and address any problems from a wide scope.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby Rails Javascript React HTML CSS SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Horizons - Github

Travel Planning and Landmark Discovery Web App

- Designed with usability in mind, potential to facilitate client to travel agent interaction
- Connected with Google Places API to perform landmark discovery

Pantry Hero - Github

Recipe Finder - Parses User provided ingredients list to find makeable Recipes

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Hooked to the Tasty API to facilitate ingredient to recipe interaction

LetterBombs (Alphabet Game) - Github

A Speed / Reaction Browser Game

Created with Ruby on Rails backend and a Javascript frontend, utilized Javascript/CSS animations

EXPERIENCE

FUSION (Fostering Unity on Stage in One Night) - Multicultural Performances

 Collaborated with the university and various clubs to arrange and bring publicity to the event, while also recruiting performers for the showcase Lehigh University 04/2015

Holi (Hindu Spring Festival)

Contacted outside services in order to provide the necessary functions for the event

Steered the event so as to prevent safety risks and other unforeseen circumstances

Lehigh University 11/2014

Cognitive Science Department

Researcher

Lehigh University 09/2012 – 12/2012

Researched and compiled information on the effects of linguistic priming on response time

Asian Cultural Society (ACS)

VP of External Affairs and Event Committee,

Lehigh University Aug 08/2011-05/2015

- Fostered and maintained relationships with new and current club members
- Coordinated with other clubs to hold university-wide educational/social events in order to increase Lehigh's awareness of a diversifying nation

Peeps for a Purpose

Just Born Quality Confections 06/2010

Participant, Pennsylvania School for Global Entrepreneurship

- Devised a draft marketing plan for the introduction of Peeps into the UK.
- Plan revolved around a donation-based sponsorship from the RSPCA

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development/Software Engineering

Manhattan, NY

01/ 2020 - 05/2020

Lehigh University

Bethlehem, PA

Packelor of Science in Picentine and Neuroscience

OR / 2011 00 / 2016

Bachelor of Science in Bioengineering and Neuroscience 08/2011 – 09/2016

Woodberry Forest School
High Honors
Woodberry Forest, VA
09/2008 – 05/2011